<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mobile on Donald Hutchison! Software Development!</title>
    <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/tags/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mobile on Donald Hutchison! Software Development!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://donaldhutchison.info/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocos2D-ObjC - Game Development Tookit for iOS</title>
      <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/cocos-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/cocos-2d/</guid>
      <description>The now defunct Cocos2D-ObjC project was a hugely successful games development library for developing iPhone games. Building on top of OpenGLES, it offered a more performant means of rendering graphics and manipulating visual objects than the UIKit based API offered by default. The scene graph API implemented in Cocos2D is now reflected in Apple&#39;s own SpriteKit framework.
After using the library for several years in a few mobile game projects, I got a position working as a full time maintainer of the library, making contributions to the core library as well as it&#39;s companion UI building app SpriteBuilder (analogous to Interface Builder for UIKit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kiekmo (Android)</title>
      <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/creations/kiekmo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/creations/kiekmo/</guid>
      <description>Kiekmo was an Android app developed for Hamburg Sparkasse and designed to bring customers physically into the branch locations by offering a free item storage system (for use with online sales ala ebay). The customer would place an item within a locker provided at a Sparkasse branch and receive a lock code via the app. The customer would then provide the code to whoever purchased their item online and conveniently let the buyer access the item at will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jelly Splash (Android &#43; iOS)</title>
      <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/creations/jelly-splash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/creations/jelly-splash/</guid>
      <description>Jelly Splash was a cross platform mobile game where the goal was to connect as many jellies as possible in order to beat the level and advance. Jelly Splash has had over 75 million players and was a huge success for Wooga.
As part of the core team, I was involved in daily feature development and maintenance. I focused heavily on the Android side in this project and was personally responsible for porting the game to the Kindle Fire store, where it was heavily featured and relatively successful given the market size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Development in the Bar</title>
      <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/blog/2014-02-02-ruby-at-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donaldhutchison.info/blog/2014-02-02-ruby-at-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>For reasons I won&#39;t get into, I found myself spending Christmas in Wick on the north east tip of Scotland. This being the second time it&#39;s occurred I was familiar with the quirks and isolation of this part of the world. One of the more upswinging things that happens is that every 26th December, there&#39;s a charity raffle in the local Seaforth Club. This is where you buy some tickets, drink, win prizes and drink some more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>