<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Donald Hutchison! Software Development!</title>
    <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Donald Hutchison! Software Development!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>anki-rb - A ruby gem to create Anki flashcards for spaced repetition learning.</title>
      <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/anki-rb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/anki-rb/</guid>
      <description>Anki is a flashcard app which uses a spaced repetition algorithm to help with memorising facts and committing items to memory.
After realising there was no library which could create flashcard decks with integrated media (which is very useful for spoken phrases and pronounciation when learning languages), I created this gem.
The gem provides a simple Ruby api to create flashcards and decks, as well as embed supported media formats (audio, images and video).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocos2D-ObjC - Game Development Tookit for iOS</title>
      <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/cocos-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/cocos-2d/</guid>
      <description>The now defunct Cocos2D-ObjC project was a hugely successful games development library for developing iPhone games. Building on top of OpenGLES, it offered a more performant means of rendering graphics and manipulating visual objects than the UIKit based API offered by default. The scene graph API implemented in Cocos2D is now reflected in Apple&#39;s own SpriteKit framework.
After using the library for several years in a few mobile game projects, I got a position working as a full time maintainer of the library, making contributions to the core library as well as it&#39;s companion UI building app SpriteBuilder (analogous to Interface Builder for UIKit).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>