<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>game development on Donald Hutchison! Software Development!</title>
    <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/tags/game-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in game development on Donald Hutchison! Software Development!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://donaldhutchison.info/tags/game-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cocos2D-ObjC - Game Development Tookit for iOS</title>
      <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/cocos-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donaldhutchison.info/projects/contributions/cocos-2d/</guid>
      <description>The now defunct Cocos2D-ObjC project was a hugely successful games development library for developing iPhone games. Building on top of OpenGLES, it offered a more performant means of rendering graphics and manipulating visual objects than the UIKit based API offered by default. The scene graph API implemented in Cocos2D is now reflected in Apple&#39;s own SpriteKit framework.
After using the library for several years in a few mobile game projects, I got a position working as a full time maintainer of the library, making contributions to the core library as well as it&#39;s companion UI building app SpriteBuilder (analogous to Interface Builder for UIKit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffeescript &#43; RequireJS Skeleton Project</title>
      <link>https://donaldhutchison.info/blog/2014-01-10-coffeescript-skeleton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donaldhutchison.info/blog/2014-01-10-coffeescript-skeleton/</guid>
      <description>After being introduced to the awesome pixi.js framework by a colleague, I decided to update an old project of mine to make screwing around with it a little easier. This skeleton project comes with everything you need to run a pretty decent setup, and all at the cost of only two command line options.
Skeleton Project! The initial configuration is usually a pain for me, so I threw together an example project and some scripts to manage this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>